Half time is game time.
Drumline is a drama, romance, comedy film directed by Charles Stone III.
A talented street drummer from Harlem enrolls in a Southern university,
expecting to lead its marching band's drumline to victory.
He initially flounders in his new world, before realizing that
it takes more than talent to reach the top.
Devon Miles, played by Nick Cannon.
Laila, played by Zoe Saldaña.
Dr. Lee, played by Orlando Jones.
Sean Taylor, played by Leonard Roberts.
Jayson, played by GQ.
Ernest, played by Jason Weaver.
Drumline is a 2002 American coming-of-age teen
comedy-drama film directed by Charles Stone III.
The screenplay, which was inspired by the Southwest Dekalb High School Marching Panthers
in Decatur, Georgia, was written by Tina Gordon Chism and Shawn Schepps.
The film follows a young drummer from New York, played by Nick Cannon, who enters the fictional
Atlanta A&T University and bumps heads with the leader of his new school's drum section.
Zoe Saldaña, Leonard Roberts and Orlando Jones co-star.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, with most of
them praising the musical bands' overall performances.
It was a success at the box office, earning over $56 million in the
U.S., and almost $1.2 million in foreign markets.
A direct sequel Drumline: A New Beat, premiered on VH1 on October 27, 2014.
Cannon reprises his role as Devon, albeit as a supporting
character rather than the protagonist.
The film explores themes of sorority, music rehearsal,
fraternity initiation, television broadcast, push ups.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.